910 N. Peck Ave • Hydro, OK 73048

ericc@pobox.com

Software developer and Product Manager with thirty two years of experience in desktop, mobile, and web development. An excellent communicator, equally comfortable speaking remotely or in-person with development teams, executive staff, partners, and third-party developers.

Primary Skills

- A deep understanding of software development and the tools and services needed by developers.
- Communicating the features and benefits of products and services to diverse audiences.
- Collaborating with strategic partners on co-marketing and shared development projects.
- Working with open-source projects to create usable experiences for developers and consumers.
- Creating an inclusive and open work environment that allows employees to reach their potential.

Education

- M.S., Computer Science, Oklahoma State University (Pending Thesis), 1989
- B.S., Computer Science, Mathematics, Southwestern Oklahoma State University, 1986

Work Experience

March 2018 – Present

Samsung Electronics

Lead, Developer Relations

- Leading the Developer Relations team at Samsung Electronics, focusing on technical content, developer marketing, developer technical support, and events.
- Managing content creation and on-site logistics for an annual developer conference that attracted 5,000 attendees prior to COVID. In 2021, the event was moved to a one-day virtual event, with my team assisting in content creation and delivery.
- Creating a data-driven approach that takes analytic data from multiple sources to identify SDKs and services that need more resources, content areas that require improvement, and an indication of third-party developer interest.
- Proposed and led a multi-year project to move multiple sites from in-house hosting to cloud infrastructure and services with modern frameworks and a mobile-friendly design. Worked with development teams and PMs at HQ to prioritize tasks. The first phase of the project launched in January 2020 as the Samsung Developers portal at https://developer.samsung.com.
- Guiding projects through a security review process requiring SOC2 compliance and external, independent auditors. Working with the security team to triage results of pen-testing and correcting issues with the development team. Assisting partner companies in having their platforms approved for use at Samsung.
- Improved the development process for websites and services by transitioning from ad-hoc delivery
 with no quality processes or documentation to one delivering scheduled monthly releases with a
 dedicated QA team. Implemented a separation between development, staging, and production
 environments with bug tracking and change control. As a result of these changes, reduced hosting
 costs and vendor contracts by 60% while improving quality and turnaround time.
- Improved security of the development environment by auditing hosting accounts and creating a transition plan to a secure environment. Researched and executed a plan based on security team recommendations to ensure proper access and networking components were properly configured.

ERIC CLONINGER

(405) 458-0458

910 N. Peck Ave • Hydro, OK 73048

ericc@pobox.com

April 2016 - March 2018

Bereavement Leave

September 2015 – April 2016

Cigital (now Synopsis)

Sr. Product Manager

- Led geographically diverse engineering team to create mobile application security testing tools.
- Designed an online portal for customers to submit mobile apps for security testing, based on an
 existing design for web application testing. Customers could manage new testing as part of a semiautomated development test flow.

August 2014 - August 2015

Samsung Electronics

Sr. Product Manager

- Designed and built a developer portal to support Android phones, smart watches, and VR devices.
- Drove developer adoption of Samsung watches with technical content and on-site training. Created videos on development tools and smartwatch development. Represented Samsung at hackathons and other live events, providing technical assistance to developers targeting Samsung technologies.
- Audited all Samsung's mobile SDKs for quality and consistency. Advised the technical teams
 responsible for the SDKs on how to improve their offerings. Recruited and led team of technical
 writers to improve Samsung's developer documentation.

April 2014 – August 2014

Coverity (Contract)

Product Marketing Manager

- Performed competitive analysis and marketing for a newly-acquired product, updating guides for field engineers and sales staff.
- Created new case studies and white papers, at the rate of one per month. Interviewed executives
 and developers at clients to understand how they used Coverity's products and how the results
 allowed them to deliver better products to their own customers.

October 2012 - March 2014

Klocwork, Inc

Principal Product Manager

- Reporting to the CTO, hired and mentored two new Product Managers in their roles focused on software security and lifecycle management.
- Guided the engineering team in transition from waterfall development to Agile, acting as Product Owner for the company's flagship product.
- Supported several high-visibility customers in creating a product development process that included static analysis. These customers represented 15% of annual revenue at the time and the success of these integrations led to more opportunities in the semiconductor market segment.

February 2008 – October 2012

Motorola Mobility

Sr. Product Manager

- Managed the creation, delivery, and launch activities for Motorola's development tools, released externally as MOTODEV Studio. Delivered quarterly feature updates on-time for 4 years, including releases timed to major product announcements or industry events.
- Led the off-shore engineering team in Brazil as Product Owner. Wrote user stories and negotiated priorities with development managers.
- Led an Eclipse open source project to create vendor-neutral mobile tools suite, working with other established leaders in the mobile industry at the time.
- Represented Motorola as a Program Committee member for the annual EclipseCon conference. Reviewed proposals for speakers to deliver presentations on mobile and embedded development.

910 N. Peck Ave • Hydro, OK 73048

ericc@pobox.com

June 2006 - February 2008

Wind River

Sr. Product Manager

- Product Owner for Wind River's Eclipse-based Workbench development tools. Created product
 planning documents and worked with engineering teams to deliver a product roadmap. Drove
 product improvements to get Workbench certified for IBM's Ready for Rational program
- Led a cross-department review of call center data and customer surveys with a goal to increase
 product quality and customer satisfaction. Discovered two product experiences, installation and
 license management, resulted in 70% of all support incidents. Using this information, proposed and
 drove product changes to improve the user experience and reduce the support incidents.

October 2005 - June 2006

Advanced Financial Solutions

Sr. Engineer

- Developed new product features for Windows-based banking backend software. Development on Windows using C++, C#, MFC, and .Net Framework.
- Performed a security audit and code quality review on existing C++ and .Net source base to
 increase quality and reliability of product lines. Discovered flaws that could've led to disclosure of
 user accounts and customer information and reported them to the CTO, along with a proposal for
 fixing the issues. Implemented the fixes with oversight from CTO and the product leads. Assisted
 product teams in integrating the fixes and delivering the updated software to affected customers.

October 1999 - July 2005

Palm/PalmSource

Sr. Engineer

- Created tools for the PalmOS SDK that were distributed to third-party app developers.
- Designed a new text-based layout language based on XML that replaced the binary format used in early versions of the Palm SDK. This format allowed developers to create their own data models for resources without new tools. Wrote conversion tools that supported the bidirectional exchange of the new and old formats to allow teams to adopt the tools at their convenience.
- As a result of the development of these tools, I discovered a flaw in PalmOS regarding how GUI controls were stored. The controls were stored in applications as 32-bit integers but were always referenced as 16-bit integers. After a tool change and rebuilding the OS and internal applications, we saved 2K of ROM space in a 128K ROM and was still backward compatible with existing apps.
- Designed and developed layout and design tools for building Palm OS GUI apps based on the new layout language. These tools were distributed internally as well as included in the PalmOS SDK.
- Created tools and Java plugins for a branded version of the Eclipse IDE that supported the development of PalmOS apps.

May 1996 – October 1999

Metrowerks

Sr. Engineer/Product Manager

- Engineering lead for Metrowerks popular CodeWarrior products, focusing on delivering new features for mobile devices and embedded systems.
- Created new products based on the CodeWarrior IDE targeting Windows, Windows CE, Palm OS, and embedded 68K processors. The Palm OS product was a significant revenue source for the company, generating almost \$2 million per year on a budget of 4 developers.
- Delivered technical presentations at conferences and customer sites.
- Authored articles for technical journals and contributed to two popular books on Palm OS.

March 1988 - May 1996

Various

Software Developer/Team Lead